

SIDDHARTH GARG

Developer, Al Engineer, CFA - Passed level 1

- @ i@siddharthgarg.in
- Hyderabad, India | Remote (Preferred)
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sidg510/

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Technology, Computer Science | VIT Vellore (Institute of Eminence)

- ****** 07/2018 06/2022
- ▼ Vellore, India
- CGPA: 9.07

12th Grade, All India Senior School Certificate Examination(AISSCE) | Delhi Public School, RK Puram

- ****** 07 2015 05 2017
- New Delhi, India
- Score: 90%

10th Grade, All India Secondary School Certificate (AISSC) | Delhi Public School, Agra

- 2015
- New Delhi, India
- CGPA: 9.4

TECH STACK

Programming

Python | SQL | JavaScript | C++ | C | Java

AI/ML

Image Recognition CNNs Sentiment Analysis

RNNs Topic Modeling Object Detection

Web Development

Django Flask NodeJS PHP ReactJS

UI/UX

 [Illustrator]
 Canva
 Adobe XD
 Photoshop

CERTIFICATIONS



Cleared Level 1 of Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Examination

TensorFlow Developer Certificate
Google's TensorFlow Developer Certificate

Skydiving

Tandem Skydiving Certificate, Pattaya

Consecutive First Prize, RCPC 2020 and 2019 Coding Competition, involving severalrounds by ACM, VIT

ABOUT ME

Started learning to write code when I was 12 years old, there was no going back from there. I enjoy my work, let it be Tech, Design or Finance, I love exploring different disciplines and developing solutions, that create value. Love to travel, been to (almost) everywhere in the country.

EXPERIENCE

Member Tech | DE Shaw India

iii Jan 2022 - 5 Mar 2024

Hyderabad, India

Acquired in-depth Finance and Technical knowledge in Fundamental equities team. Developed and maintained ETL pipelines for multiple alternative data sources, which were used to generate trading signals in both systematic and discretionary models. Also developed a data validation framework from scratch to reduce noise from the generated signal, additionally reducing time from 1hr to 12mins.

Intern Member Tech | DE Shaw India

iii May 2021 - July 2021

Remote (Hyderabad Office)

Developed an extendible python application for tracking different internal tools' performance. Worked with Elastic, Logstash, Influx and Kibana.

Computer Vision Engineer | FindMind Analytics

= Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Programmed a high accuracy end to end pipeline with a REST API for OCR and masking of clients' sensitive documents using object detection, increasing speed 30x and accuracy to 97% from 60% _______

Deep Learning Head | The Symbionic Company

May 2020 - Sep 2020

Produced a Dataset and Developed a deeplearning based object detection model for recognizing different grip patterns, to be fed into a 3D prosthetic robotic hand.

Marketing Head, Vellore Executive Board & Volunteer | ERIDE (NGO)

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Vellore, India

Empowering Rural India with Digital Education(ERIDE) aims on delivering digital literacy to underprivileged people. Joined as a freshman, from teaching kids in orphanages, community centres to leading the NGO as a board member

PROJECTS

Malware Family classification using Convolutional Neural Networks on Byte Sequences |

GUI based End to End Auto ML dashboard for object detection and masking. | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

REST API for OCR and masking of sensitive data in Identity documents using image processing and object detection | Ownership transferred to FindMind Analytics

Sentiment Analysis and Topic Modelling of primetime News-hourDebates from different news channels

TB Saathi (Tuberculosis Diagnosis using neural networks tool) | ## | 2nd Prize in Hello World Hack